<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Malte Dewies</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/dewies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/dewies/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD candidate at the Erasmus School of Social and Behavioural Sciences. My research focuses on the use of psychological insights for public policy (behavioural public policy). For this, I am part of the Behavioural Insights Group Rotterdam. In this group behavioural scientists like me work together with policy experts from the municipality of Rotterdam on case studies submitted by the municipality.
I have experience with conducting field experiments and evaluation studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Fleur Helmink</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/helmink/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/helmink/</guid>
      <description>Description Fleur Helmink is a PhD Candidate at Erasmus MC-Sophia. She works on the Dutch Bipolar Offspring Study, a cohort study that follows adolescents of parents with bipolar disorder into adulthood. Fleur uses innovative methods, such as experience sampling method and digital phenotyping (with the use of smartphone sensors), to measure daily life functioning.
She specifically focusses on how mental health and daily life functioning relate in high-risk individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar: Introduction to Git(Hub)</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/intro-github-apr2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/intro-github-apr2020/</guid>
      <description>Our first online ReproducibiliTea Rotterdam was a great success! Thirty people joined our Zoom meeting to discuss with Anne Scheel her preprint comparing the standard psychology literature with Registered Reports. The presentation was awesome, the questions insightful, and the atmosphere light and informal. Thanks to everyone involved!
Given the strong interest and current relevance of open science as a set of tools to quickly disseminate knowledge, the OSCR will host an online webinar entitled Introduction to Git(Hub).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReproducibiliTea Online: Comparing the standard Psychology literature with Registered Reports</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/reproducibilitea-apr2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/reproducibilitea-apr2020/</guid>
      <description>The worldwide spread of the SARS-CoV-2 virus – and subsequent increase in people affected by COVID-19 – is causing noticeable disruptions in our regular lifestyle. However, we are doing our best to translate OSCR initiatives online, not only to continue our mission to increase awareness on open science practices but also provide valuable support and human connection during this period of (self-)isolation.
One of our first online events will be the sixth OSCR ReproducibiliTea journal club, which will take place on April 8th at 11:001.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR &amp; R.I.O.T.S.: by researchers, for researchers</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/oscr-riots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/oscr-riots/</guid>
      <description>The Open Science Community Rotterdam is part of a national (Dutch) network of communities created by researchers for researchers.
All Open Science Communities in The Netherlands as of March 2020. Image by Anita Eerland, licensed under CC BY-ND 3.0
 We facilitate communication among scholars by giving them platforms to connect and share information on open science practices, for example our internal chat rooms on Matrix or the website on which this blog post is hosted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Suzanne van de Groep</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/vandegroep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/vandegroep/</guid>
      <description>Description Suzanne van de Groep is a PhD candidate studying the behavioral and neural development of prosocial behavior in adolescence. She is specifically interested in how social contextual factors (e.g., familiarity and audience effects) and individual differences influence giving and other forms of prosociality; and how this is reflected in adolescents’ brains. For her PhD project, Suzanne is involved in all stages (e.g., design, ethical approval, data collection, analyses, writing) of the Brainlinks study, a comprehensive longitudinal study on prosocial development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Dorien Huijser</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/huijser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/huijser/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a lab and data manager at a developmental psychology group at ESSB, meaning that I help researchers implement better data management and more open research practices. This can sometimes be a challenge, because we collect large amounts of data that are often also privacy-sensitive. I for example help our researchers with preregistration, data organization and data sharing and aim to develop a vision on open science for our group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Michelle Achterberg</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/achterberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/achterberg/</guid>
      <description>Description Michelle Achterberg works on a large longitudinal twin study on brain development in childhood and emerging adolescence. Within this study Michelle specifically focusses on longitudinal brain development and it’s relation to social information processing and behavioral control. Additionally, she is expanding her knowledge of functional and structural brain connectivity and investigates how brain development is influenced by genes and the environment.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Elisabet Blok</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/blok/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/blok/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student at ErasmusMC-Sophia, focusing on children with a combination of anxiety, depression, attention problems and aggressive behavior, defined as the Dysregulation Phenotype (DP). I am looking at symptom and brain development and the bidirectional relationship between the two over time in children and adolescents drawn from the general population. I am also the co-funder of Rotterdam R.I.O.T. Science Club, a community providing training in Reproducible, Interpretable, Open, and Transparent science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Lorenza Dall&#39;Aglio</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/dallaglio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/dallaglio/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student at Erasmus MC investigating how brain structure and connectivity relate with behavioural and emotional problems in children and adolescents from the general population. I am also the co-funder of Rotterdam R.I.O.T. Science Club, a community providing training in Reproducible, Interpretable, Open, and Transparent science.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReproducibiliTea: Responsible Research Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/reproducibilitea-mar2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/reproducibilitea-mar2020/</guid>
      <description>The fifth OSCR ReproducibiliTea journal club will take place on March 11th at 11:00 in room G2-35 (G building).
We will have a special guest: Hardy Schwamm, Open Scholarship Librarian at the National University of Ireland and co-founder of the Open Scholarship Community Galway. Hardy is interested in how research is evaluated and how academics are assessed when it comes to job / grant applications and promotions. Hardy believes that research assessment is a topic all researchers should have a basic knowledge of, as it will determine their careers in academia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Ana Martinovici</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/martinovici/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/martinovici/</guid>
      <description>Description I have a strong interest in methods that facilitate high quality research: reproducible, replicable, relevant, and communicated in a clear and responsible manner also to non-scientific audiences. In terms of substantive interests, my research focuses on dynamic aspects of consumer decision making, more specifically on how preferences evolve over time until a final choice is expressed. In order to gain access to these latent processes, I am using dynamic Bayesian models calibrated on eye-tracking data, building on research in neuroeconomics that supports a strong link between attention and decision making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Rik Joosen</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/joosen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/joosen/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD candidate at the Department of Public Administration and Sociology. In my research, I look at interest groups and regulatory politics using quantitative text analysis and statistics. I am fairly new to open science. I have published in an open access journal and use open source software (R) for my analysis.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Steven Verheyen</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/verheyen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/verheyen/</guid>
      <description> Description My work on individual differences in language use is positioned at the intersection of quantitative psychology, philosophy of language, and cognitive linguistics. I have expertise in the fields of concepts and categories, semantics, and psychometrics.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.
     
 Expertise  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReproducibiliTea: Meet the Journal of Trial and Error</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/reproducibilitea-feb2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/reproducibilitea-feb2020/</guid>
      <description>The fourth OSCR ReproducibiliTea journal club will take place on February 12th at 11:00 in room J7-55 (Bayle building).
We will have two special guests: Max Bautista Perpinyà and Stefan Gaillard, two co-founders of the Journal of Trial and Error. In their talk1, Max and Stefan will focus on the importance of publishing negative and null results, as well as other research results that would traditionally be considered “failure” such as unsuccessful chemical syntheses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Open Science Festival - Save the Date!</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/osfestival-wageningen-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/osfestival-wageningen-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Website: https://opensciencefestival.nl/
Deadlines:
Open Call submission: March 10th, 2020
Notification of acceptance or rejection: March 31st, 2020
Registration opens: April 2nd, 2020
The National Open Science Festival provides researchers the opportunity to learn about the benefits of different Open Science practices. It is a place to meet peers that are already working openly or that are interested to start doing so. Key to this day is sharing knowledge and best practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming talk by Daniël Lakens</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/dpecs-lakens-feb2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/dpecs-lakens-feb2020/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to announce that Daniël Lakens, Associate Professor in the Human-Technology interaction group at Eindhoven University of Technology, will give a talk at the upcoming DPECS colloquium, which will take place on February 11th at 15:00 in room T13-67 (Mandeville building).
Prof. Lakens is a long-standing adopter and proponent of open science practices. He is active on Twitter, has a very interesting blog called The 20% Statistician, and teaches two successful massive online open courses: Improving your statistical inferences and Improving Your Statistical Questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReproducibiliTea: Musical Contrast and Chronological Rejuvenation</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/reproducibilitea-jan2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/reproducibilitea-jan2020/</guid>
      <description>The third OSCR ReproducibiliTea journal club will take place on January 22nd at 11:00 in room VB-02 (V building). I will be the discussant, and we will talk about the following paper1:
 Simmons, J. P., Nelson, L. D., &amp;amp; Simonsohn, U. (2011). False-Positive Psychology: Undisclosed Flexibility in Data Collection and Analysis Allows Presenting Anything as Significant. Psychological Science, 22(11), 1359–1366. https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797611417632
 This paper, now considered a classic reference when discussing open science in psychological research, shows how unreported flexible choices in data collection, analysis, and reporting can increase false-positive rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Marianne Tenand</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/tenand/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/tenand/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a post-doctoral researcher at Erasmus School of Health Policy &amp;amp; Management (ESHPM). My background is in social sciences and applied economics. My current research focuses on the economics aspects of population ageing, in particular on the provision of long-term care services to the elderly.
I exploit individual-level data of different types: surveys conducted by Statistical Institutes, administrative register data, or client databases, which I access under confidentially agreements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Yuna Koyama</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/12/koyama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/12/koyama/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student and my research field is social epidemiology. My main interests is how social environment affects child mental health and development. Open science is new to me but I am sure that it improves the science quality as a whole and efficiency in research as well.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Joran Jongerling</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/jongerling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/jongerling/</guid>
      <description>Description I specialize in Multilevel Analysis, Bayesian statistics, Timeseries, Network Analysis, and Diary Studies. My research theme is “Inter-individual differences in intra-individual variability. How do individuals change over time, and how does this change differ between individuals?”.
I mainly work on longitudinal modeling and simulation studies, but also collaborate with substantive researchers and PhD’s (mainly form the field of Psychology, Child- and Educational Sciences) whenever I can.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReproducibiliTea for qualitative researchers</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/reproducibilitea-dec2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/reproducibilitea-dec2019/</guid>
      <description>As many of you know, OSCR recently started a ReproducibiliTea journal club (for details on the initiative, see a previous blog post). Seven people attended our first meeting (on November 13th): everyone was interested and engaged, thanks to a cozy and informal environment conducive of open debate… we could not have started in a better way! This nice atmosphere sparked very interesting discussions, one of which is the topic of our next meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: L. Paloma Rojas Saunero</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/rojassaunero/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/rojassaunero/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student at the Epidemiology Department of Erasmus MC, my research is focused on the application of causal inference methods in dementia research. I am also an R enthusiastic (R-Ladies R’dam organizer) and advocate of open science.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk on Collective and Individual Benefits of Open Science at ESHPM</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/introos-eshpm-oct2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/introos-eshpm-oct2019/</guid>
      <description>On October 31st I will discuss the benefits of open science (and open data in particular) with researchers working at the Erasmus School of Health Policy and Management (ESHPM).
I will first provide a brief introduction on open science and some active areas of development. Afterwards, I will show examples from psychology, economy, and health sciences on how non-transparent scholarly output – combined with the current sluggish and cumbersome publication system – can lead to failed large-scale replications, computational errors, and delayed dissemination of information, with tangible societal consequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Aurélie Lemmens</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/lemmens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/lemmens/</guid>
      <description>Description My current research focuses on the development of predictive and prescriptive analytics to address key business decisions. I am particularly interested in the design of new methodologies that can guide organizations in their customer-centric decision making. My research portfolio has been organized according to the three fundamental stages of the customer lifecycle: (i) customer acquisition and new product introduction, (ii) customer development and engagement, and (iii) customer retention. A substantial part of my research involves machine learning and large-scale cluster and grid computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReproducibiliTea journal clubs</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/oscr-reproducibilitea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/oscr-reproducibilitea/</guid>
      <description>Exciting news! OSCR will organize monthly journal clubs following the ReproducibiliTea format!
Here you will find a brief description of how the OSCR ReproducibiliTea will be organized. In brief, each month we will meet for an hour either in T (Mandeville) or J (Bayle) building to discuss a paper or blog post treating a specific open science topic. Some examples may include:
 does publishing open access have specific costs and benefits for the individual researcher?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Aleksandra Badura</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/badura/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/badura/</guid>
      <description>Description Throughout my Ph.D. studies and Postdoctoral Fellowships, my work had focused on unraveling the function of the cerebellum in health and disease, encompassing two research lines:
 Line-1. I have established that the modulation of cerebellar activity is essential for motor learning and helped to develop a computer model that reproduces experimental data and can predict motor impairments based on neural activity. Using intravital two-photon imaging, we discovered that granule cells acquire signals predictive of motor performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Meg Perry-Duxbury</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/perryduxbury/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/perryduxbury/</guid>
      <description>Description My background is applied economics, specifically health economics. My work focuses on opportunity costs in the economic evaluation on health care interventions. I use predominantly pre-collected aggregate data sets, however I also have some experience with Big Data and Survey Data.
I’m fairly new to the Open Science environment, and I am most interested in learning about data management, preregistration and reproducibility.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSF Workshop at ESHPM</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/09/osfworkshop-eshpm-sept2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/09/osfworkshop-eshpm-sept2019/</guid>
      <description>On September 24th I will give a workshop on how to use the Open Science Framework (OSF), a collaborative web tool allowing scholars from all disciplines to upload and share the products of their research, e.g., data, materials, analysis protocols, and article preprints.
I have already given a similar workshop at the Faculty of Economics and Business Administration at Ghent University and the Erasmus Research Institute of Management here at EUR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Gabriele Paolacci</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/paolacci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/paolacci/</guid>
      <description>Description My research considers both substantive and methodological questions in behavioral research. I conduct experiments to study whether and how people’s decisions (e.g., what to buy, whom to donate) deviate from the prescriptions of rational choice theory and consequentialist philosophy. I also do research into the methodology of data collection in the behavioral sciences, and in particular the use of online samples (e.g., MTurk).
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Rolf Zwaan</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/zwaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/zwaan/</guid>
      <description>Description My research is in the area of language processing and cognition. Current interests are conspiracy thinking and social media use.
I conduct mostly behavioral research on language processing, memory, and learning. I have been an active participant in the open science movement for the past 6 years or so, focusing particularly on replication, on which I’ve written both theoretical and empirical papers as well as blog posts. My students and I routinely use preregistration for our experiments and always make our stimuli and data available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Jason Roos</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/roos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/roos/</guid>
      <description>Description My research considers questions in the areas of entertainment and information goods, digital advertising, and other online phenomena. I am especially interested in settings where information, learning, and other types of adaptation affect choice. I am also interested in meta-science, and have an active research stream studying how behavioral scientists conduct experiments.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Matthias Wieser</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/wieser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/wieser/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a psychologist with a strong background in experimental and biological psychology. Using human electrophysiology and affective psychophysiology, I am trying to figure out the (neuro-)cognitive and affective processes underlying core aspects of social vision, aversive learning, cognition-emotion interactions, emotional reactivity, and pain perception. In the context of experimental psychopathology, I apply this basic knowledge obtained from studies of healthy populations to better delineate the dysfunctions of (neuro-)cognitive and affective processes in pathological fear, anxiety, and pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Wilfred Mijnhardt</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/mijnhardt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/mijnhardt/</guid>
      <description> Description My role is institutional advancement of the business school at Erasmus University.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.
     
 Expertise  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OSCR website is live!</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/website-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/website-live/</guid>
      <description>The official website of the Open Science Community Rotterdam is now live!
Have you heard of this community but you don’t really know what we do? On the Home page you can find our mission and scope.
Who are the members of our community? Click on People to find the member list and a brief description of their expertise. This section will rapidly be updated with new profiles, so make sure to check it out often!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/coc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/coc/</guid>
      <description>Code of Conduct Antonio Schettino
Mission The Open Science Community Rotterdam (OSCR) organizes and promotes formal and informal events and meetings to discuss open and transparent scientific practices (also termed open science, OS). OSCR has three main goals:
 facilitate communication and sharing of information on OS; increase and speed up the practical adoption of OS; build professional networks and foster scientific collaborations, with OS as an integral part of research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/home/</guid>
      <description>Who are we? The Open Science Community Rotterdam (OSCR) comprises of academics and support staff working at Erasmus University Rotterdam (EUR) and Erasmus Medical Center (ErasmusMC). Our common goal is to promote and adopt open and transparent scientific practices at every stage of the research cycle, from the initial idea to the final product. For further details, please check out our Code of Conduct.
OSCR is part of a growing national network of communities including Amsterdam, Utrecht, Leiden, Tilburg, Maastricht, Eindhoven, Nijmegen, and Groningen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Oliver Lindemann</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/07/lindemann/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/07/lindemann/</guid>
      <description>Description I’m a psychologist and teaching statistics at the EUR. As an experimental psychologist, my research interest focuses on the cognitive representation of numbers and mental arithmetics, the role of sensorimotor codes in knowledge representations as well as Bayesian approaches to data analyses and computational modelling.
I’m actively promoting the idea of Open Science in all my research activities and have been part of several large-scale replication projects. I’m especially interested in methodological issues and problems of data sharing and the question of data integrity in open science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Antonio Schettino</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/04/schettino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/04/schettino/</guid>
      <description>Description I have a background in experimental psychology, cognitive and affective electrophysiology. During my academic career, I investigated the relationship between emotions and visual perception using a wide range of methodological and statistical tools. I adopted transparent and open science practices at every stage of the research cycle, from the preregistration of the initial idea to the publication of the final manuscript in peer-reviewed open access journals.
As Coordinator of the Open Science Community Rotterdam, I facilitate communications between members of the community, organize events and workshops, communicate such activities on social media, and personally support individual researchers and research groups with day-to-day activities related to open science.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>