<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>home on Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/categories/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in home on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/categories/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/home/</guid>
      <description>Who are we? The Open Science Community Rotterdam (OSCR) comprises academics and support staff working at Erasmus University Rotterdam (EUR) and Erasmus Medical Center (ErasmusMC). Our common goal is to discuss, promote, and adopt open and transparent scientific practices at every stage of the research cycle, from the initial idea to the final product. For further details, please check out our Guiding Principles.
OSCR is part of the International Network of Open Science &amp;amp; Scholarship Communities (INOSC), including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/coc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/coc/</guid>
      <description>Code of Conduct OSCs organize, promote, and facilitate open science events to enable all participants, members and non-members, to learn about, share, and discuss open science practices. The purpose of this Code of Conduct (CoC) is to enable an environment in which diverse individuals can collaborate and interact in mutual respect. We recognize a shared responsibility to create and maintain that environment for the benefit of all.
Some behaviors, therefore, are specifically prohibited both in person and online:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/principles/</guid>
      <description>Guiding Principles  Open Science/Scholarship Communities (OSCs) are bottom-up platforms by and for researchers to exchange knowledge and know-how on open science practices OSCs are inclusive  Researchers are the target audience of OSCs, but students, researcher supporters, and others that are interested in (conducting) research are also welcome to join the community No prior knowledge is required to be part of the community, nor are members in any way required to commit to certain open science/scholarship practices   OSCs organize, promote, and facilitate open science/scholarship events to (1) learn about and discuss open science/scholarship practices; (2) share open science/scholarship knowledge; and (3) build professional networks  Events are open to members and non-members and, if possible, are free-of-charge Attendees and organizers of events organized by OSCs must adhere to the Code of Conduct   OSCs promote critical discussions of pro’s and con’s of open science/scholarship practices.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
