<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source Software on Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/open-source-software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source Software on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/open-source-software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: L. Paloma Rojas Saunero</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/oscr-ppl-rojassaunero/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/oscr-ppl-rojassaunero/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student at the Epidemiology Department of Erasmus MC, my research is focused on the application of causal inference methods in dementia research. I am also an R enthusiastic (R-Ladies R’dam organizer) and advocate of open science.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Aleksandra Badura</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/oscr-ppl-badura/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/oscr-ppl-badura/</guid>
      <description>Description Throughout my Ph.D. studies and Postdoctoral Fellowships, my work had focused on unraveling the function of the cerebellum in health and disease, encompassing two research lines:
 Line-1. I have established that the modulation of cerebellar activity is essential for motor learning and helped to develop a computer model that reproduces experimental data and can predict motor impairments based on neural activity. Using intravital two-photon imaging, we discovered that granule cells acquire signals predictive of motor performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Oliver Lindemann</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/07/oscr-ppl-lindemann/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/07/oscr-ppl-lindemann/</guid>
      <description>Description I’m a psychologist and teaching statistics at the EUR. As an experimental psychologist, my research interest focuses on the cognitive representation of numbers and mental arithmetics, the role of sensorimotor codes in knowledge representations as well as Bayesian approaches to data analyses and computational modelling.
I’m actively promoting the idea of Open Science in all my research activities and have been part of several large-scale replication projects. I’m especially interested in methodological issues and problems of data sharing and the question of data integrity in open science.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>