<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>School Essb on Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/school-essb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in School Essb on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/school-essb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Andrik Becht</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/06/becht/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/06/becht/</guid>
      <description>Description Andrik Becht is a postdoctoral researcher in the SYNC lab and at the Youth &amp;amp; Family department, Utrecht University. His research is specifically aimed at understanding adolescents’ identity development from both a neurobiological and contextual perspective (for instance, examining the role of parents and peers). Andrik also investigates possible consequences of ongoing identity uncertainty in adolescence, to ultimately answer the question why some adolescents thrive whereas others don’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Eduard Klapwijk</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/05/klapwijk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/05/klapwijk/</guid>
      <description>Description Eduard is a postdoc in the SYNC lab. A central question in his research is: Why do most teenagers grow up to be kind to others while a proportion engage in harmful, antisocial and risky behaviors? He is very much interested in how we can address these questions using neuroimaging methods in a robust, reproducible way. His main focus as a postdoc at Erasmus University will be to determine the optimal sample size in developmental studies for a range of fMRI tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Malte Dewies</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/dewies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/dewies/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD candidate at the Erasmus School of Social and Behavioural Sciences. My research focuses on the use of psychological insights for public policy (behavioural public policy). For this, I am part of the Behavioural Insights Group Rotterdam. In this group behavioural scientists like me work together with policy experts from the municipality of Rotterdam on case studies submitted by the municipality.
I have experience with conducting field experiments and evaluation studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Suzanne van de Groep</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/vandegroep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/vandegroep/</guid>
      <description>Description Suzanne van de Groep is a PhD candidate studying the behavioral and neural development of prosocial behavior in adolescence. She is specifically interested in how social contextual factors (e.g., familiarity and audience effects) and individual differences influence giving and other forms of prosociality; and how this is reflected in adolescents’ brains. For her PhD project, Suzanne is involved in all stages (e.g., design, ethical approval, data collection, analyses, writing) of the Brainlinks study, a comprehensive longitudinal study on prosocial development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Dorien Huijser</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/huijser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/huijser/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a lab and data manager at a developmental psychology group at ESSB, meaning that I help researchers implement better data management and more open research practices. This can sometimes be a challenge, because we collect large amounts of data that are often also privacy-sensitive. I for example help our researchers with preregistration, data organization and data sharing and aim to develop a vision on open science for our group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Michelle Achterberg</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/achterberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/achterberg/</guid>
      <description>Description Michelle Achterberg works on a large longitudinal twin study on brain development in childhood and emerging adolescence. Within this study Michelle specifically focusses on longitudinal brain development and it’s relation to social information processing and behavioral control. Additionally, she is expanding her knowledge of functional and structural brain connectivity and investigates how brain development is influenced by genes and the environment.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Rik Joosen</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/joosen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/joosen/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD candidate at the Department of Public Administration and Sociology. In my research, I look at interest groups and regulatory politics using quantitative text analysis and statistics. I am fairly new to open science. I have published in an open access journal and use open source software (R) for my analysis.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Steven Verheyen</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/verheyen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/verheyen/</guid>
      <description> Description My work on individual differences in language use is positioned at the intersection of quantitative psychology, philosophy of language, and cognitive linguistics. I have expertise in the fields of concepts and categories, semantics, and psychometrics.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.
     
 Expertise  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Joran Jongerling</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/jongerling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/jongerling/</guid>
      <description>Description I specialize in Multilevel Analysis, Bayesian statistics, Timeseries, Network Analysis, and Diary Studies. My research theme is “Inter-individual differences in intra-individual variability. How do individuals change over time, and how does this change differ between individuals?”.
I mainly work on longitudinal modeling and simulation studies, but also collaborate with substantive researchers and PhD’s (mainly form the field of Psychology, Child- and Educational Sciences) whenever I can.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Rolf Zwaan</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/zwaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/zwaan/</guid>
      <description>Description My research is in the area of language processing and cognition. Current interests are conspiracy thinking and social media use.
I conduct mostly behavioral research on language processing, memory, and learning. I have been an active participant in the open science movement for the past 6 years or so, focusing particularly on replication, on which I’ve written both theoretical and empirical papers as well as blog posts. My students and I routinely use preregistration for our experiments and always make our stimuli and data available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Matthias Wieser</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/wieser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/wieser/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a psychologist with a strong background in experimental and biological psychology. Using human electrophysiology and affective psychophysiology, I am trying to figure out the (neuro-)cognitive and affective processes underlying core aspects of social vision, aversive learning, cognition-emotion interactions, emotional reactivity, and pain perception. In the context of experimental psychopathology, I apply this basic knowledge obtained from studies of healthy populations to better delineate the dysfunctions of (neuro-)cognitive and affective processes in pathological fear, anxiety, and pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Oliver Lindemann</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/07/lindemann/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/07/lindemann/</guid>
      <description>Description I’m a psychologist and teaching statistics at the EUR. As an experimental psychologist, my research interest focuses on the cognitive representation of numbers and mental arithmetics, the role of sensorimotor codes in knowledge representations as well as Bayesian approaches to data analyses and computational modelling.
I’m actively promoting the idea of Open Science in all my research activities and have been part of several large-scale replication projects. I’m especially interested in methodological issues and problems of data sharing and the question of data integrity in open science.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>