<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Access on Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/open-access/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Access on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/open-access/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Georg Granic</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/07/granic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/07/granic/</guid>
      <description>Description My research interests lie in the intersection of Economics, Political Science, and Psychology. I am currently doing research on how incentives influence survey responses, how voting affects political preferences, and how to design just-in-time adaptive nudges.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Asimina Aslanidou</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/06/aslanidou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/06/aslanidou/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD candidate in Experimental Psychopathology at the Department of Psychology, Education and Child Studies at Erasmus University Rotterdam. My research focuses on factors that influence how people generalize their fear across different objects/people/situations that they encounter in everyday life. I compare several psychophysiological and brain measures and the goal is to understand what makes fear generalization turn from a helpful trait to a maladaptive symptom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Suzanne van de Groep</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/vandegroep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/vandegroep/</guid>
      <description>Description Suzanne van de Groep is a PhD candidate studying the behavioral and neural development of prosocial behavior in adolescence. She is specifically interested in how social contextual factors (e.g., familiarity and audience effects) and individual differences influence giving and other forms of prosociality; and how this is reflected in adolescents’ brains. For her PhD project, Suzanne is involved in all stages (e.g., design, ethical approval, data collection, analyses, writing) of the Brainlinks study, a comprehensive longitudinal study on prosocial development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Dorien Huijser</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/huijser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/huijser/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a lab and data manager at a developmental psychology group at ESSB, meaning that I help researchers implement better data management and more open research practices. This can sometimes be a challenge, because we collect large amounts of data that are often also privacy-sensitive. I for example help our researchers with preregistration, data organization and data sharing and aim to develop a vision on open science for our group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Marianne Tenand</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/tenand/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/tenand/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a post-doctoral researcher at Erasmus School of Health Policy &amp;amp; Management (ESHPM). My background is in social sciences and applied economics. My current research focuses on the economics aspects of population ageing, in particular on the provision of long-term care services to the elderly.
I exploit individual-level data of different types: surveys conducted by Statistical Institutes, administrative register data, or client databases, which I access under confidentially agreements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Aleksandra Badura</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/badura/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/badura/</guid>
      <description>Description Throughout my Ph.D. studies and Postdoctoral Fellowships, my work had focused on unraveling the function of the cerebellum in health and disease, encompassing two research lines:
 Line-1. I have established that the modulation of cerebellar activity is essential for motor learning and helped to develop a computer model that reproduces experimental data and can predict motor impairments based on neural activity. Using intravital two-photon imaging, we discovered that granule cells acquire signals predictive of motor performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Meg Perry-Duxbury</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/perryduxbury/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/perryduxbury/</guid>
      <description>Description My background is applied economics, specifically health economics. My work focuses on opportunity costs in the economic evaluation on health care interventions. I use predominantly pre-collected aggregate data sets, however I also have some experience with Big Data and Survey Data.
I’m fairly new to the Open Science environment, and I am most interested in learning about data management, preregistration and reproducibility.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Rolf Zwaan</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/zwaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/zwaan/</guid>
      <description>Description My research is in the area of language processing and cognition. Current interests are conspiracy thinking and social media use.
I conduct mostly behavioral research on language processing, memory, and learning. I have been an active participant in the open science movement for the past 6 years or so, focusing particularly on replication, on which I’ve written both theoretical and empirical papers as well as blog posts. My students and I routinely use preregistration for our experiments and always make our stimuli and data available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Matthias Wieser</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/wieser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/wieser/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a psychologist with a strong background in experimental and biological psychology. Using human electrophysiology and affective psychophysiology, I am trying to figure out the (neuro-)cognitive and affective processes underlying core aspects of social vision, aversive learning, cognition-emotion interactions, emotional reactivity, and pain perception. In the context of experimental psychopathology, I apply this basic knowledge obtained from studies of healthy populations to better delineate the dysfunctions of (neuro-)cognitive and affective processes in pathological fear, anxiety, and pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Wilfred Mijnhardt</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/mijnhardt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/mijnhardt/</guid>
      <description> Description My role is institutional advancement of the business school at Erasmus University.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.
     
 Expertise  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>