<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Access on Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/open-access/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Access on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/open-access/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Rolf Zwaan</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/oscr-ppl-zwaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/oscr-ppl-zwaan/</guid>
      <description>Description My research is in the area of language processing and cognition. Current interests are conspiracy thinking and social media use.
I conduct mostly behavioral research on language processing, memory, and learning. I have been an active participant in the open science movement for the past 6 years or so, focusing particularly on replication, on which I’ve written both theoretical and empirical papers as well as blog posts. My students and I routinely use preregistration for our experiments and always make our stimuli and data available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Matthias Wieser</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/oscr-ppl-wieser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/oscr-ppl-wieser/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a psychologist with a strong background in experimental and biological psychology. Using human electrophysiology and affective psychophysiology, I am trying to figure out the (neuro-)cognitive and affective processes underlying core aspects of social vision, aversive learning, cognition-emotion interactions, emotional reactivity, and pain perception. In the context of experimental psychopathology, I apply this basic knowledge obtained from studies of healthy populations to better delineate the dysfunctions of (neuro-)cognitive and affective processes in pathological fear, anxiety, and pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Wilfred Mijnhardt</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/oscr-ppl-mijnhardt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/oscr-ppl-mijnhardt/</guid>
      <description> Description My role is institutional advancement of the business school at Erasmus University.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.
     
 Open Science Expertise  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>