<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reproducibilitea on Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/reproducibilitea/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reproducibilitea on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/reproducibilitea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ReproducibiliTea: Reponsible Research Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/reproducibilitea-mar2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/reproducibilitea-mar2020/</guid>
      <description>The fifth OSCR ReproducibiliTea journal club will take place on March 11th at 11:00 in room G2-35 (G building).
We will have a special guest: Hardy Schwamm, Open Scholarship Librarian at the National University of Ireland and co-founder of the Open Scholarship Community Galway. Hardy is interested in how research is evaluated and how academics are assessed when it comes to job / grant applications and promotions. Hardy believes that research assessment is a topic all researchers should have a basic knowledge of, as it will determine their careers in academia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReproducibiliTea: Meet the Journal of Trial and Error</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/reproducibilitea-feb2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/reproducibilitea-feb2020/</guid>
      <description>The fourth OSCR ReproducibiliTea journal club will take place on February 12th at 11:00 in room J7-55 (Bayle building).
We will have two special guests: Max Bautista Perpinyà and Stefan Gaillard, two co-founders of the Journal of Trial and Error. In their talk1, Max and Stefan will focus on the importance of publishing negative and null results, as well as other research results that would traditionally be considered “failure” such as unsuccessful chemical syntheses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReproducibiliTea: Musical Contrast and Chronological Rejuvenation</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/reproducibilitea-jan2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/reproducibilitea-jan2020/</guid>
      <description>The third OSCR ReproducibiliTea journal club will take place on January 22nd at 11:00 in room VB-02 (V building). I will be the discussant, and we will talk about the following paper1:
 Simmons, J. P., Nelson, L. D., &amp;amp; Simonsohn, U. (2011). False-Positive Psychology: Undisclosed Flexibility in Data Collection and Analysis Allows Presenting Anything as Significant. Psychological Science, 22(11), 1359–1366. https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797611417632
 This paper, now considered a classic reference when discussing open science in psychological research, shows how unreported flexible choices in data collection, analysis, and reporting can increase false-positive rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReproducibiliTea for qualitative researchers</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/reproducibilitea-dec2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/reproducibilitea-dec2019/</guid>
      <description>As many of you know, OSCR recently started a ReproducibiliTea journal club (for details on the initiative, see a previous blog post). Seven people attended our first meeting (on November 13th): everyone was interested and engaged, thanks to a cozy and informal environment conducive of open debate… we could not have started in a better way! This nice atmosphere sparked very interesting discussions, one of which is the topic of our next meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReproducibiliTea journal clubs</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/oscr-reproducibilitea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/oscr-reproducibilitea/</guid>
      <description>Exciting news! OSCR will organize monthly journal clubs following the ReproducibiliTea format!
Here you will find a brief description of how the OSCR ReproducibiliTea will be organized. In brief, each month we will meet for an hour either in T (Mandeville) or J (Bayle) building to discuss a paper or blog post treating a specific open science topic. Some examples may include:
 does publishing open access have specific costs and benefits for the individual researcher?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>