<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Management on Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/data-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Management on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/data-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Ilse van de Groep</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/06/ivandegroep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/06/ivandegroep/</guid>
      <description>Description Ilse van de Groep is a PhD Candidate at the SYNC lab (Erasmus University Rotterdam) and the Child and Adolescent Psychiatry Department (Amsterdam UMC, location VUmc). In her PhD project, Ilse examines several mechanisms that underlie distinct developmental trajectories of social and antisocial behavior in emerging adulthood, with a specific focus on the neural correlates of self-concept, vicarious reward learning, social evaluation and aggression regulation.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Andrik Becht</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/06/becht/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/06/becht/</guid>
      <description>Description Andrik Becht is a postdoctoral researcher in the SYNC lab and at the Youth &amp;amp; Family department, Utrecht University. His research is specifically aimed at understanding adolescents’ identity development from both a neurobiological and contextual perspective (for instance, examining the role of parents and peers). Andrik also investigates possible consequences of ongoing identity uncertainty in adolescence, to ultimately answer the question why some adolescents thrive whereas others don’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Eduard Klapwijk</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/05/klapwijk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/05/klapwijk/</guid>
      <description>Description Eduard is a postdoc in the SYNC lab. A central question in his research is: Why do most teenagers grow up to be kind to others while a proportion engage in harmful, antisocial and risky behaviors? He is very much interested in how we can address these questions using neuroimaging methods in a robust, reproducible way. His main focus as a postdoc at Erasmus University will be to determine the optimal sample size in developmental studies for a range of fMRI tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Ilaria Orlandi</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/05/orlandi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/05/orlandi/</guid>
      <description>Description Broadly speaking, my research interests lie in the field of strategic leadership and corporate governance. I am interested in developing our understanding of directors’ appointments and motivation to accept this job position. As an early stage scholar (PhD candidate), I am moving my first steps into open science and I look forward to seeing it developing while being a part of it.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Malte Dewies</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/dewies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/dewies/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD candidate at the Erasmus School of Social and Behavioural Sciences. My research focuses on the use of psychological insights for public policy (behavioural public policy). For this, I am part of the Behavioural Insights Group Rotterdam. In this group behavioural scientists like me work together with policy experts from the municipality of Rotterdam on case studies submitted by the municipality.
I have experience with conducting field experiments and evaluation studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Fleur Helmink</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/helmink/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/04/helmink/</guid>
      <description>Description Fleur Helmink is a PhD Candidate at Erasmus MC-Sophia. She works on the Dutch Bipolar Offspring Study, a cohort study that follows adolescents of parents with bipolar disorder into adulthood. Fleur uses innovative methods, such as experience sampling method and digital phenotyping (with the use of smartphone sensors), to measure daily life functioning.
She specifically focusses on how mental health and daily life functioning relate in high-risk individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Suzanne van de Groep</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/vandegroep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/vandegroep/</guid>
      <description>Description Suzanne van de Groep is a PhD candidate studying the behavioral and neural development of prosocial behavior in adolescence. She is specifically interested in how social contextual factors (e.g., familiarity and audience effects) and individual differences influence giving and other forms of prosociality; and how this is reflected in adolescents’ brains. For her PhD project, Suzanne is involved in all stages (e.g., design, ethical approval, data collection, analyses, writing) of the Brainlinks study, a comprehensive longitudinal study on prosocial development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Dorien Huijser</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/huijser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/huijser/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a lab and data manager at a developmental psychology group at ESSB, meaning that I help researchers implement better data management and more open research practices. This can sometimes be a challenge, because we collect large amounts of data that are often also privacy-sensitive. I for example help our researchers with preregistration, data organization and data sharing and aim to develop a vision on open science for our group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Michelle Achterberg</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/achterberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/achterberg/</guid>
      <description>Description Michelle Achterberg works on a large longitudinal twin study on brain development in childhood and emerging adolescence. Within this study Michelle specifically focusses on longitudinal brain development and it’s relation to social information processing and behavioral control. Additionally, she is expanding her knowledge of functional and structural brain connectivity and investigates how brain development is influenced by genes and the environment.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Marianne Tenand</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/tenand/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/tenand/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a post-doctoral researcher at Erasmus School of Health Policy &amp;amp; Management (ESHPM). My background is in social sciences and applied economics. My current research focuses on the economics aspects of population ageing, in particular on the provision of long-term care services to the elderly.
I exploit individual-level data of different types: surveys conducted by Statistical Institutes, administrative register data, or client databases, which I access under confidentially agreements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Yuna Koyama</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/12/koyama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/12/koyama/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student and my research field is social epidemiology. My main interests is how social environment affects child mental health and development. Open science is new to me but I am sure that it improves the science quality as a whole and efficiency in research as well.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: L. Paloma Rojas Saunero</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/rojassaunero/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/rojassaunero/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student at the Epidemiology Department of Erasmus MC, my research is focused on the application of causal inference methods in dementia research. I am also an R enthusiastic (R-Ladies R’dam organizer) and advocate of open science.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Aleksandra Badura</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/badura/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/badura/</guid>
      <description>Description Throughout my Ph.D. studies and Postdoctoral Fellowships, my work had focused on unraveling the function of the cerebellum in health and disease, encompassing two research lines:
 Line-1. I have established that the modulation of cerebellar activity is essential for motor learning and helped to develop a computer model that reproduces experimental data and can predict motor impairments based on neural activity. Using intravital two-photon imaging, we discovered that granule cells acquire signals predictive of motor performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Gabriele Paolacci</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/paolacci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/paolacci/</guid>
      <description>Description My research considers both substantive and methodological questions in behavioral research. I conduct experiments to study whether and how people’s decisions (e.g., what to buy, whom to donate) deviate from the prescriptions of rational choice theory and consequentialist philosophy. I also do research into the methodology of data collection in the behavioral sciences, and in particular the use of online samples (e.g., MTurk).
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Jason Roos</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/roos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/roos/</guid>
      <description>Description My research considers questions in the areas of entertainment and information goods, digital advertising, and other online phenomena. I am especially interested in settings where information, learning, and other types of adaptation affect choice. I am also interested in meta-science, and have an active research stream studying how behavioral scientists conduct experiments.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Wilfred Mijnhardt</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/mijnhardt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/mijnhardt/</guid>
      <description> Description My role is institutional advancement of the business school at Erasmus University.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.
     
 Expertise  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>