<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Management on Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/data-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Management on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/data-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Dorien Huijser</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/huijser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/03/huijser/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a lab and data manager at a developmental psychology group at ESSB, meaning that I help researchers implement better data management and more open research practices. This can sometimes be a challenge, because we collect large amounts of data that are often also privacy-sensitive. I for example help our researchers with preregistration, data organization and data sharing and aim to develop a vision on open science for our group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Marianne Tenand</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/tenand/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/tenand/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a post-doctoral researcher at Erasmus School of Health Policy &amp;amp; Management (ESHPM). My background is in social sciences and applied economics. My current research focuses on the economics aspects of population ageing, in particular on the provision of long-term care services to the elderly.
I exploit individual-level data of different types: surveys conducted by Statistical Institutes, administrative register data, or client databases, which I access under confidentially agreements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Yuna Koyama</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/12/koyama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/12/koyama/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student and my research field is social epidemiology. My main interests is how social environment affects child mental health and development. Open science is new to me but I am sure that it improves the science quality as a whole and efficiency in research as well.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: L. Paloma Rojas Saunero</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/rojassaunero/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/rojassaunero/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student at the Epidemiology Department of Erasmus MC, my research is focused on the application of causal inference methods in dementia research. I am also an R enthusiastic (R-Ladies R’dam organizer) and advocate of open science.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Aleksandra Badura</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/badura/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/badura/</guid>
      <description>Description Throughout my Ph.D. studies and Postdoctoral Fellowships, my work had focused on unraveling the function of the cerebellum in health and disease, encompassing two research lines:
 Line-1. I have established that the modulation of cerebellar activity is essential for motor learning and helped to develop a computer model that reproduces experimental data and can predict motor impairments based on neural activity. Using intravital two-photon imaging, we discovered that granule cells acquire signals predictive of motor performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Gabriele Paolacci</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/paolacci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/paolacci/</guid>
      <description>Description My research considers both substantive and methodological questions in behavioral research. I conduct experiments to study whether and how people’s decisions (e.g., what to buy, whom to donate) deviate from the prescriptions of rational choice theory and consequentialist philosophy. I also do research into the methodology of data collection in the behavioral sciences, and in particular the use of online samples (e.g., MTurk).
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Jason Roos</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/roos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/roos/</guid>
      <description>Description My research considers questions in the areas of entertainment and information goods, digital advertising, and other online phenomena. I am especially interested in settings where information, learning, and other types of adaptation affect choice. I am also interested in meta-science, and have an active research stream studying how behavioral scientists conduct experiments.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Wilfred Mijnhardt</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/mijnhardt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/mijnhardt/</guid>
      <description> Description My role is institutional advancement of the business school at Erasmus University.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.
     
 Expertise  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>