<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Preregistration on Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/preregistration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Preregistration on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/preregistration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Matthias Wieser</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/oscr-ppl-wieser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/08/oscr-ppl-wieser/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a psychologist with a strong background in experimental and biological psychology. Using human electrophysiology and affective psychophysiology, I am trying to figure out the (neuro-)cognitive and affective processes underlying core aspects of social vision, aversive learning, cognition-emotion interactions, emotional reactivity, and pain perception. In the context of experimental psychopathology, I apply this basic knowledge obtained from studies of healthy populations to better delineate the dysfunctions of (neuro-)cognitive and affective processes in pathological fear, anxiety, and pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Antonio Schettino</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/04/oscr-ppl-schettino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/04/oscr-ppl-schettino/</guid>
      <description>Description I have a background in experimental psychology, cognitive and affective electrophysiology. During my academic career, I investigated the relationship between emotions and visual perception using a wide range of methodological and statistical tools. I adopted transparent and open science practices at every stage of the research cycle, from the preregistration of the initial idea to the publication of the final manuscript in peer-reviewed open access journals.
As Coordinator of the Open Science Community Rotterdam, I facilitate communications between members of the community, organize events and workshops, communicate such activities on social media, and personally support individual researchers and research groups with day-to-day activities related to open science.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>