<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>School Erasmusmc on Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/school-erasmusmc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in School Erasmusmc on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/school-erasmusmc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Lorenza Dall&#39;Aglio</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/dallaglio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/dallaglio/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student at Erasmus MC investigating how brain structure and connectivity relate with behavioural and emotional problems in children and adolescents from the general population. I am also the co-funder of Rotterdam RIOT Science Club, a community providing training in Reproducible, Interpretable, Open, and Transparent science.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Yuna Koyama</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/12/koyama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/12/koyama/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student and my research field is social epidemiology. My main interests is how social environment affects child mental health and development. Open science is new to me but I am sure that it improves the science quality as a whole and efficiency in research as well.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: L. Paloma Rojas Saunero</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/rojassaunero/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/rojassaunero/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student at the Epidemiology Department of Erasmus MC, my research is focused on the application of causal inference methods in dementia research. I am also an R enthusiastic (R-Ladies R’dam organizer) and advocate of open science.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Aleksandra Badura</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/badura/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/badura/</guid>
      <description>Description Throughout my Ph.D. studies and Postdoctoral Fellowships, my work had focused on unraveling the function of the cerebellum in health and disease, encompassing two research lines:
 Line-1. I have established that the modulation of cerebellar activity is essential for motor learning and helped to develop a computer model that reproduces experimental data and can predict motor impairments based on neural activity. Using intravital two-photon imaging, we discovered that granule cells acquire signals predictive of motor performance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>