<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Open Science Community Rotterdam</title>
    <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Open Science Community Rotterdam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Elisabet Blok</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/blok/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/blok/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student at ErasmusMC-Sophia, focusing on children with a combination of anxiety, depression, attention problems and aggressive behavior, defined as the Dysregulation Phenotype (DP). I am looking at symptom and brain development and the bidirectional relationship between the two over time in children and adolescents drawn from the general population. I am also the co-funder of Rotterdam RIOT Science Club, a community providing training in Reproducible, Interpretable, Open, and Transparent science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Lorenza Dall&#39;Aglio</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/dallaglio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/dallaglio/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student at Erasmus MC investigating how brain structure and connectivity relate with behavioural and emotional problems in children and adolescents from the general population. I am also the co-funder of Rotterdam RIOT Science Club, a community providing training in Reproducible, Interpretable, Open, and Transparent science.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Ana Martinovici</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/martinovici/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/martinovici/</guid>
      <description>Description I have a strong interest in methods that facilitate high quality research: reproducible, replicable, relevant, and communicated in a clear and responsible manner also to non-scientific audiences. In terms of substantive interests, my research focuses on dynamic aspects of consumer decision making, more specifically on how preferences evolve over time until a final choice is expressed. In order to gain access to these latent processes, I am using dynamic Bayesian models calibrated on eye-tracking data, building on research in neuroeconomics that supports a strong link between attention and decision making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Rik Joosen</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/joosen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/02/joosen/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD candidate at the Department of Public Administration and Sociology. In my research, I look at interest groups and regulatory politics using quantitative text analysis and statistics. I am fairly new to open science. I have published in an open access journal and use open source software (R) for my analysis.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Marianne Tenand</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/tenand/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2020/01/tenand/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a post-doctoral researcher at Erasmus School of Health Policy &amp;amp; Management (ESHPM). My background is in social sciences and applied economics. My current research focuses on the economics aspects of population ageing, in particular on the provision of long-term care services to the elderly.
I exploit individual-level data of different types: surveys conducted by Statistical Institutes, administrative register data, or client databases, which I access under confidentially agreements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Joran Jongerling</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/jongerling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/jongerling/</guid>
      <description>Description I specialize in Multilevel Analysis, Bayesian statistics, Timeseries, Network Analysis, and Diary Studies. My research theme is “Inter-individual differences in intra-individual variability. How do individuals change over time, and how does this change differ between individuals?”.
I mainly work on longitudinal modeling and simulation studies, but also collaborate with substantive researchers and PhD’s (mainly form the field of Psychology, Child- and Educational Sciences) whenever I can.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: L. Paloma Rojas Saunero</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/rojassaunero/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/11/rojassaunero/</guid>
      <description>Description I am a PhD student at the Epidemiology Department of Erasmus MC, my research is focused on the application of causal inference methods in dementia research. I am also an R enthusiastic (R-Ladies R’dam organizer) and advocate of open science.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email. The icons on the right redirect to the CV and social media pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Aurélie Lemmens</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/lemmens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/lemmens/</guid>
      <description>Description My current research focuses on the development of predictive and prescriptive analytics to address key business decisions. I am particularly interested in the design of new methodologies that can guide organizations in their customer-centric decision making. My research portfolio has been organized according to the three fundamental stages of the customer lifecycle: (i) customer acquisition and new product introduction, (ii) customer development and engagement, and (iii) customer retention. A substantial part of my research involves machine learning and large-scale cluster and grid computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCR Member: Meg Perry-Duxbury</title>
      <link>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/perryduxbury/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.openscience-rotterdam.com/2019/10/perryduxbury/</guid>
      <description>Description My background is applied economics, specifically health economics. My work focuses on opportunity costs in the economic evaluation on health care interventions. I use predominantly pre-collected aggregate data sets, however I also have some experience with Big Data and Survey Data.
I’m fairly new to the Open Science environment, and I am most interested in learning about data management, preregistration and reproducibility.
 CV and Contact Info Click on the picture to send an email.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>